Hello and welcome to this video in which we'll
look at the importance of sharing knowledge,
information, and performance measures with
other members of the team and other groups.
Sharing information and knowledge can
increase the productivity of a team that
helps it to work faster and smarter.
Sharing knowledge will generate improvement
ideas and ensure the best methods are
applied to work practices or processes.
Let's take a look at these
three areas in more detail.
Let's start by thinking back to teams
and their strengths and weaknesses.
We learned that each individual within
a team has different skills that they
bring to the team and for good, productive
teams, these compliment each other.
While the same applies to knowledge,
different people within an organisation or
team bring with them their own knowledge.
Some may know a little information for what's
needed, others may be experts, and some may
not know anything for the particular topic.
For example, imagine you are asked to join
a team to brainstorm where a new product
hasn't been as successful as expected.
On that team, some people will have
been involved in the initial idea
and carried it though to deployment.
Others may work in customer services
and be the ones receiving complaints.
Other team members may not know much about the
product but have experience of problem solving.
By sharing their experiences and knowledge,
the team can collaboratively work together
to understand what's gone wrong and
discuss solutions to improve the product.
Information sharing.
Let's begin by looking at how
information differs from knowledge.
Knowledge that we've already looked
at is deeper than information.
Knowledge draws on experience and expertise.
It's the wisdom a person has from
knowing a lot about a subject.
Information on the other hand is the
data or instructions that anyone can
pick up from a sheet, as an example.
Think about baking a cake.
Anyone can get the information for how to
bake a cake from a recipe and instructions.
It's only those with knowledge of
baking that know how to turn it into a
successful cake that you can't wait to try.
Within our team of problem solvers, customer
services can prepare information that's been
gathered from customer complaints and feedback.
This may be displayed in a graph,
survey or verbally passed on.
Those with the knowledge of how and why
the product was developed can use this
information to understand what's gone wrong.
By collaborating together, all members
of team can share their information
and knowledge to reach a solution.
Performance measures allow an organization
to know if things are going right.
They have targets that tell the
management if expectations are being met.
In our example, they are used as a tool to know
if the new product is as successful as expected.
By setting a target that a certain number
of units will be sold within, say the first
three months, or that it will score a three
stars on TripAdvisor in the same timeframe,
the company can monitor its success.
So not only has the customer service department
received a lot of complaints, the product
is also below its performance Measures.
By bringing together the information
gathered by customer service and the
performance measures, the team can share
their knowledge to solve the initial product
difficulties and develop a successful product.